Finding Aid for Ann Arbor Garden Club Records 1930-1965
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann Arbor Garden Club Records 1930-1965
Ann Arbor Garden Club
1 linear ft. and 1 oversize folder
Reports of the club's presidents and treasurers, committee reports, constitution and by-laws, membership records, and bulletins, 1933-1965.
85618; Bn.2/2; UBN.2m
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The Ann Arbor Garden Club (donor no. 1912 ) first began depositing records in 1957. Periodic additions have been received.
The record group is open for research.
Founded in the late 1920's, the Ann Arbor Garden Club focused on the fundamentals and problems of gardening. As the organization grew, it began to sponsor annual flower shows, school gardening programs, and garden therapy work. One of the original members of the Federated Garden Clubs of Michigan, the Ann Arbor club has supported many phases of the Federation's state-wide and national activities.
Both the internal workings and activities of the group are well documented in this record group. The records, 1930-1965, include a constitution and by-laws, minutes, 1933-1952, reports of the club's presidents and treasurers committee reports, flower show material, bulletins, and clippings. Illustrative of some women's activities during the 1930's, 40's and 50's, the record group also provides insights into local Ann Arbor history. The records, left in their original order for the most part, reflect the organization and activities of the club.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor Garden Club.; Gardening.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Ann Arbor Garden Club.; Exhibitions.; Gardens.; Yost Field House (University of Michigan)
Genre/Form:
Photographs
- History, bylaws, officers files
  - History of the Ann Arbor Garden Club (Box 1)
  - Proposed By-laws, 1957 constitution, undated (Box 1)
  - Secretary's book, 1933-1939 (Box 1)
  - Loose papers from Secretary's book, 1933, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Secretary's book, 1930-1952 (Box 1)
  - Loose papers from Secretary's book;, 1944 undated (Box 1)
  - President's reports, 1931, 1949-1951, undated (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's book, 1930-1957 (Box 1)
- Committees
  - Civic Center Committee, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Conservation Committee, 1933-1935 (Box 1)
  - Garden Visiting Committee, 1934-1943 (Box 1)
  - Membership Committee reports and list, 1933-1946 (Box 1)
  - Nominating Committee, 1935 (Box 1)
  - School Garden Committee, 1939-1945 (Box 1)
- Flower Shows
  - Flower Show, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Flower Show, 1938, (includes photographs) (Box 1)
  - Flower Show, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Clippings from Flower Show, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Flower Show, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Flower Show, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Flower Show, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Flower Show, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Flower Show, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Special Events, 1943-1965 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous and other activities
  - Meetings of the Federated Garden Clubs of Michigan in Ann Arbor, 1948, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Bulletins, 1933-1943 (Box 1)
  - Bulletins, 1944-1953 (Box 1)
  - Bulletins, 1954-1965 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1944-1954 (Box 1)
  - Awards and Citations (Box 1)
  - Clippings:, 1937, 1939, 1950-1962 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1950-1951 (Box 1)
  - Publications (Box 1)
  - Wines Junior Garden Club Scrapbook, 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Wines Junior Garden Club Scrapbook, 1959-1960 (Box 1)
  - Photographs of gardening exhibits (Box 1)
  - Photographs of gardening exhibits (Folder UBN.2m)